<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AR on The NickEvents Blog</title>
    <link>https://evann362.github.io/tags/ar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AR on The NickEvents Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:10:37 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://evann362.github.io/tags/ar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Les Abysses et La Laisse de mer</title>
      <link>https://evann362.github.io/posts/xrdev03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:10:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://evann362.github.io/posts/xrdev03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While at the LOREM we collaborated with Galerie Abstract Project to implement a glimpse of our internal projects. Augemented Reality and UV images were integrated into the Abyss Expo&#xA;.&#xA;The artists wanted to gather various objects that we&amp;rsquo;d often imagine to be found at the bottom of the sea. Humans leave so many beach items, trash, and trinquets that sink to the very abyss. There was a desire to use Augmented reality which has a way of transforming the experience of the gallery. We settled on QR codes around the space and outside that when scanned revealed signs of growing sea life. Tentacles or wavy seaweed spread all over the gallery and outside.&#xA;The idea came from glancing at my computer when I was working in Touchdesigner following a workflow to build this sort of tentacle-like living thing.&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/liC-rbcEs6c?controls=1&amp;rel=0&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xA;This was Touchdesigner so I could not exactly export an animated 3d model for use in Unity. I had searched for a day and a half to figure out how I can reproduce this in Blender with the same fluid mouvement as I got in TD. I&amp;rsquo;d use GeoNodes but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to export a model with animation but eventually I came across a tuto on how to animate a flag. Seeing the ability to influence the fabric&amp;rsquo;s bones so fluidly with the physics simulations seemed extremely tedious but when it&amp;rsquo;s done once it&amp;rsquo;s easily tweekable for other projects.&#xA;I built the app in Unity and created several image targets I drew up shortly in the time allotted for this project. The final implementation after I mapped the space and tested in the gallery space was just to implement a video recording function. We provided a selection of UV printed images for exhibiting. Tablets were used to make the experience more shared.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
